Guide to the Michele Zackheim Papers MSS.108
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series III: Einstein
  - Subseries D: Correspondence
    - Anderson, Kathy, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 313)
    - Angst, Jules, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 314)
    - Ansmeyer, Holle, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 315)
    - Antonov, Anatole, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 316)
    - Attorneys in Belgrade, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 317)
    - Baron, Alexander, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 318)
    - Beck, Anna, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 319)
    - Benton, Judy, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 320)
    - Berg, Gunner, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 321)
    - Bernstein, Jeremy, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 322)
    - Bolli, Silvana, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 323)
    - Briggs, Lord, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 324)
    - Bruce, Colin, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 325)
    - Bywater, Michael, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 326)
    - Canby, Peter, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 327)
    - Carter, Paul, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 328)
    - Cash, Alana, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 329)
    - Castanigetti, Giuseppe, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 330)
    - Collins, Becky, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 331)
    - Court, Arnold, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 332)
    - Dokmanovic, Marija, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 333)
    - Dokmanovic, Milos, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 334)
    - Dokmanovic, Slavica, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 335)
    - Eichelsheim, Julia, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 336)
    - Einstein, Evelyn, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 337)
    - Elias, James, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 338)
    - Elliott, Cynthia, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 339)
    - Elsenbein, Stefan, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 340)
    - Erne, Emil, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 341)
    - Evans, Jonathan, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 342)
    - Feil, Katharina, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 343)
    - Gaperva, Elena, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 344)
    - Gastpar, Huldrych, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 345)
    - Glaus, Beat, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 346)
    - Goodmaker, Andrea, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 347)
    - Grendelmeir, Marie, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 348)
    - Gross, Amy, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 349)
    - Guardian, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 350)
    - Guisolan, Michel, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 351)
    - Halpern, Joel, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 352)
    - Harrison, Cary, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 353)
    - Hartley, Mary, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 354)
    - Herschdoerfer, Mrs., undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 355)
    - Highfield, Roger, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 356)
    - Hogg, J, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 357)
    - Holton, Gerald, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 358)
    - Howald, Marianne, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 359)
    - Howard, Don, undated; 31142040610704 (Box 7, Folder 360)
    - Jankovic, Ivan, undated (Box 8, Folder 361)
    - Kontic, Mirko, undated (Box 8, Folder 362)
    - Kosanovic, Dragana, undated (Box 8, Folder 363)
    - Kristic, Dord (George), undated (Box 8, Folder 364)
    - Kupermine, Jean-Claude, undated (Box 8, Folder 365)
    - Lazic, Momir, undated (Box 8, Folder 366)
    - Landenmann, Fritz, undated (Box 8, Folder 367)
    - Lauper, Marin, undated (Box 8, Folder 368)
    - Levy, Judith, undated (Box 8, Folder 369)
    - Lottman, Herbert R., undated (Box 8, Folder 370)
    - Lucas, Carol, undated (Box 8, Folder 371)
    - Lyons, Jacqui, undated (Box 8, Folder 372)
    - Maissen, Anna Pia, undated (Box 8, Folder 373)
    - Maric Family Members, undated (Box 8, Folder 374)
    - Marsh, Paul, undated (Box 8, Folder 375)
    - Marzani, Charlotte, undated (Box 8, Folder 376)
    - Mayorek, Yoram, undated (Box 8, Folder 377)
    - Meichle, Adolf, undated (Box 8, Folder 378)
    - Mendoza, Irene, undated (Box 8, Folder 379)
    - Minder, Bernard, undated (Box 8, Folder 380)
    - Montague, Lieselotte, undated (Box 8, Folder 381)
    - Moor, Jeanette, undated (Box 8, Folder 382)
    - Mutel, Connie, undated (Box 8, Folder 383)
    - Naylor, David, undated (Box 8, Folder 384)
    - Nields, Nerissa, undated (Box 8, Folder 385)
    - Niles, Charles, undated (Box 8, Folder 386)
    - Nishimoto, Sonja, undated (Box 8, Folder 387)
    - Nooter, Eric, undated (Box 8, Folder 388)
    - Overbye, Dennis, undated (Box 8, Folder 389)
    - Pais, Abraham, undated (Box 8, Folder 390)
    - Palmor, Sarah, undated (Box 8, Folder 391)
    - Pellet, Volner, undated (Box 8, Folder 392)
    - Perry, John Curtis, undated (Box 8, Folder 393)
    - Petrovic, Jelena, undated (Box 8, Folder 394)
    - Pfaffenbichler, Matthias, undated (Box 8, Folder 395)
    - Popovic, Milan, undated (Box 8, Folder 396)
    - Preuss, Sabine, undated (Box 8, Folder 397)
    - Pyenson, Lewis, undated (Box 8, Folder 398)
    - Recktman, Mark, undated (Box 8, Folder 399)
    - Reiter, Erich, undated (Box 8, Folder 400)
    - Renn, Jrgen, undated (Box 8, Folder 401)
    - Rosmarin, Ian, undated (Box 8, Folder 402)
    - Salamon, Clandine, undated (Box 8, Folder 403)
    - Saric, Nada, undated (Box 8, Folder 404)
    - Schulman, Robert, undated (Box 8, Folder 405)
    - Serbian Patriarchy, undated (Box 8, Folder 406)
    - Shaham, Nathan, undated (Box 8, Folder 407)
    - Sherry, Peggy, undated (Box 8, Folder 408)
    - Shillaker, Jane, undated (Box 8, Folder 409)
    - Shulman, Alix, undated (Box 8, Folder 410)
    - Siegel, Judy, undated (Box 8, Folder 411)
    - Simpson, Murray, undated (Box 8, Folder 412)
    - Sloane, Ave, undated (Box 8, Folder 413)
    - Sonderegger, Eva-Meili, undated (Box 8, Folder 414)
    - Stachel, John, undated (Box 8, Folder 415)
    - Stajic, Marina, undated (Box 8, Folder 416)
    - Stefanovic, Ivana, undated (Box 8, Folder 417)
    - Strickland, Lee S., undated (Box 8, Folder 418)
    - Thury, Levente, undated (Box 8, Folder 419)
    - Trbuhovic, Ljubomir, undated (Box 8, Folder 420)
    - Trmel-Plotz, Senta, undated (Box 8, Folder 421)
    - Vallis, Eleanor, undated (Box 8, Folder 422)
    - Walker, Evan Harris, undated (Box 8, Folder 423)
    - Weiss, H, undated (Box 8, Folder 424)
    - Wiegel, Robert, undated (Box 8, Folder 425)
    - Wild, Alexander, undated (Box 8, Folder 426)
    - Williams, Robin, undated (Box 8, Folder 427)
    - Yamagihara, Hanya, undated (Box 8, Folder 428)
    - Partial/Missing Name, undated (Box 8, Folder 429)
  - Subseries E: Publicity Material
    Publicity materials to promote Einstein's Daughter. Arranged alphabetically by material.
    - Author's Questionnaire, undated (Box 8, Folder 430)
    - Blurbs (requested and received), undated (Box 8, Folder 431)
    - Readings and Interviews, undated (Box 8, Folder 432)
    - Zackheim Biography, undated (Box 8, Folder 433)
  - Subseries F: Media
    Includes a combination of audiovisual and born digital material of recorded interviews, one videotape and two zip discs containing research material. Stored in box 9.
    - VHS videocassette titled "Einstein", undated (Box Shared Fales 121, Vhs 108.0008)
    - 2 100 MB Zip Discs (graphic files), undated (Box Shared Fales 120, Disk 108.0009-108.0010)
    - 1 audiocassette dated November 9, 1999 (Box Shared Fales 161, Cassette 108.0007)
    - Audio micro-cassettes documenting interviews with sources., undated (Box Shared Fales 161, Cassette 108.0001-108.0006, 108.0011-108.0028, Box 23)
    - Floppy disks (Box 23)
  - Subseries G: Photographs
    Contains original photographs of the Einstein family, duplicates of originals, photocopies and pictures documenting Zackheim's research trips, also contains negatives for some of the photographs. Originals and negatives were removed to box 10. The contents of research binder #4 were transferred to box 11. Where applicable, Zackheim's original notes and annotations have been kept with the original documents.
    - Unidentified mounted Photograph, undated (Box 8, Folder 434)
    - Photo photocopies, undated (Box 8, Folder 435)
    - Photo photocopies-Annotated List, undated (Box 8, Folder 436)
    - Photo photocopies-w/map, notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 437)
    - 140 photographs, 2 contact sheets, 35mm negatives: 7 complete and 12 incomplete sets, 2 4x5 negatives, undated (Box 10)
    - Research Binder #4, undated (Box 11)
  - Subseries H: Administrative
    Administrative files related to the research and production of Einstein's Daughter. Contains invoices and other bookkeeping documents and records.
    - Biographer Authorization, undated (Box 8, Folder 438)
    - Elfenbein, Stefan, undated (Box 8, Folder 439)
    - Putnam Letters of Notification, undated (Box 8, Folder 440)
    - Transcription Estimate, undated (Box 8, Folder 441)
  - Subseries I: Miscellaneous
    Other files related to the research and production of Einstein's Daughter.
    - Association of Jewish Refugees Information, March 1998 (Box 8, Folder 442)
    - Cards/Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 443)
    - St. Mary's Medical Center, undated (Box 8, Folder 444)
    - "Einstein's Daughter"-anonymous song lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 445)
    - Untitled poetry MS, undated (Box 8, Folder 446)
    - Untitled typescript, undated (Box 8, Folder 447)
    - Reviews, correspondence, German contract, 1995-2000 (Box 19, Folder 14-17)
- Series IV: Albert Einstein Family Correspondence Trust
  Contains legal documents, correspondence and other materials relating to Evelyn Einstein's lawsuit against the trust. Arranged in three subseries.
  - Subseries A: Legal Documents
    Includes depositions, wills, declarations, and other legal documents. Arranged alphabetically by party name.
    - Einstein, Bernard-Petition, November 29, 1996, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Einstein, Evelyn-Deposition, V 1, March 1, 1996, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Einstein, Evelyn-Deposition, V 2, March 15, 1996, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Einstein, Evelyn-Deposition, V 3, March 21, 1996, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Einstein, Evelyn-Deposition, V 4, August 2, 1996, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Einstein, Thomas-Deposition, November 8, 1995, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Einstein, Thomas-PetitionNovember 18, 1996, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Ferguson, Michael C.-Deposition, December 6, 1995, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Ferguson, Michael C.-Resignation as Trustee, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Minute Order, April 16, 1996, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Shayne, Linda-Deposition, June 8, 1996, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Stipulation and Order, April 3, 1996, 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Subseries B: Correspondence
    Contains correspondence relating to the lawsuit, a majority sourced from Evelyn Einstein's lawyer, Quentin Kopp. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - Dick, Randall, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Freud, Nicholas, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Einstein, Evelyn, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Hamill, Nancy, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Kopp, Quentin, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Mutel, Connie, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Shaw, Gregory, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Solorio, Ditas, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Subseries D: Miscellaneous
    Contains other materials related to the case including press clippings.
    - News Clippings, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Notes, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Travel Expenses, undated; 31142040610712 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Series V: Miscellaneous
  Scope and Contents
  Miscellaneous writing assignments and projects.
  - Subseries A: Writings
    Miscellaneous writing and research projects
    - Shrines and sacred places exhibitions, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Writing- The Cafe Series, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Misc. Writing- "Creativity", undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Writing- "Auschwitz" essay, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Writing- "Masks", undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Misc. Writing- essay drafts, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Misc. Writing- "The Friend", undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Writing- notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Misc. Writing- poems, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Writing- poems, manuscripts and typescript drafts, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Writing- poems, manuscripts and typescript drafts, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Research clippings, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Writing- "Sitting in a Cafe", undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Novel-"Mary Cole," research articles, photocopies, manuscript, 2000-2003 (Box 19, Folder 1-7, Box 20, Box 21)
    - The Path to Nuclear Fission: The Story of Lise Meitner and Otto Hahn, 2002-2005 (Box 19, Folder 8-12, Box 23)
    - Reviews of M. Zackheim's works, 1999-2014 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Broken Colors promotional materials, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Subseries B: Visual Arts
    Miscellaneous visual art projects
    - Visual arts- artist photos, Frankfurter, Alexander, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Visual arts- "Arts in Dialogue", undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Budapest show- correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Budapest show- flyers, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Budapest show- press, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Visual art- "Cafe Series" on PBS, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Visual art- "Cafe Series" correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Visual art- "Cafe Series" Inquiries, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Visual art- "Cafe Series" letters of interest, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Visual art- "Cafe Series" - showed interest but refused, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Visual art- "Cafe Series" to follow up, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Visual art- correspondence, "Frontiers", undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Visual art- correspondence, Gallery/museum rejextion letters, undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Visual art, correspondence: Hall, Maeve, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Visual art, correspondence: Kubicele, Ramon, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Visual art, correspondence: Northern Lights, undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Visual art, correspondence: University gallery rejection letters, undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Visual art, correspondence: University gallery rejection letters, undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Visual art, correspondence: misc., undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Visual art, correspondence: missing, partial names, undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Visual art, misc- Denver show, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Visual art, folio samples, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Visual art, Hebrew Union College, undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Visual art, Idaho Show, undated (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Visual art, Lovejoy, Margot, undated (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Visual art, Museum of American Jewish History, undated (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Visual arts- Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Visual art, Platt Gallery Show, undated (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Visual art, Sangrede Cristo Arts and Conference Center, "Inherited Dreams", undated (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Visual art, Santa Fe Festival of the Arts, undated (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Visual art, "Signal" magazine, undated (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Visual art, Silk Screening, undated (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Visual art, The Tent of Meaning, undated (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - University of Wyoming Show, undated (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Visual art, Warsaw Show, undated (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - Visual art, Idaho Show, undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Subseries C: Miscellaneous
    Miscellaneous items relating to visual art or writing projects
    - Abraham Brothers correspondence- Poet's House, undated (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - Abraham Brothers, Jeffery Newell manuscript, undated (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - VHS tapes: GM Corporate Commercials (2 copies), 2007 (Box 23)